<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstats on Mailund on the Internet</title>
    <link>https://mailund.dk/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstats on Mailund on the Internet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 - Thomas Mailund</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:23:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mailund.dk/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overscoping and eval</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/eval-and-overscoping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:23:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/eval-and-overscoping/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I used the lm function for an example of scope rules, but I left a few details out. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to muddy the example with too many details, so I choice to lie a little.
The drawing I used to explain the example was this:
  I explained how scope is implemented using environments that are chained through parent pointers, and how a function has an environment associated with it. This environment is the environment where you define the function.
When you call a function, it gets its own instance environment (for historical reasons more than anything else we call this the call frame, but it is really just a new environment).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoping Rules and NSE</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/scoping-rules-and-nse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 05:00:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/scoping-rules-and-nse/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, I wrote some tweets about how you have to be careful about scopes when you do non-standard evaluation. I cover this in both Metaprogramming in R and Domain-Specific Languages in R, but this tweet
Comprehensive overview of NSE. Should be of interest to @ThomasMailund @MilesMcBain @_ColinFay and @edwin_thoen https://t.co/2uI1HSnfEN
&amp;mdash; Deemah 🇺🇦 🇳🇴 (@dmi3k) September 17, 2018  made me write about it again—only this time in a twitter thread.
Well, I say thread—I don&amp;rsquo;t actually know how to do that, it seams; I just replied to the tweet a bunch of times and apparently that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make a thread, it therefore my reply was hard to read.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>