<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computational Thinking on Mailund on the Internet</title>
    <link>https://mailund.dk/tags/computational-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computational Thinking on Mailund on the Internet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 - Thomas Mailund</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 16:41:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mailund.dk/tags/computational-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises (CT chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 16:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter3/</guid>
      <description>I have cleaned up the exercises for chapter three of Introduction to Computational Thinking. I’m still not exactly sure how best to provide them to my students, or if I can figure out some way to automatically test answers so they can be more interactive, but I have listed them below. I have listed my answers below the exercises, so if you want to do the exercises, then stop in time.
Exercises for “Introduction to Algorithms” Below or above Here&amp;rsquo;s a game you can play with a friend: one of you think of a number between 1 and 20, both 1 and 20 included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity Exercises</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-complexity-exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 10:20:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-complexity-exercises/</guid>
      <description>In the second lesson that I teach in our Computational Thinking in Bioinformatics I cover algorithmic complexity. It is chapter four in my (draft) book on the topic: Introduction to Computational Thinking.
I have put exercises and my answers to them on GitHub. I still haven’t figured out the best way to give them to the students yet, but the can always read them on GitHub and download the source files where needed.
Anyway, I know I always make mistakes both in phrasing the exercises and in answering them—not always substantial errors, but still. So if you have some time left and if you are interested in the topic, I would love to hear if there any obvious mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides for Computational Thinking (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/compbio-chapter-3-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 13:40:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/compbio-chapter-3-slides/</guid>
      <description>I’m teaching four weeks of a class called Computational Thinking in Bioinformatics this year (the other weeks are taught by colleagues).
It is this class that got me started on my book on the topic: Introduction to Computational Thinking. I have finished the chapters I need for the class—chapters three, four, five, seven and nine—but there is still a looong way to go before the book is done.
Anyway, I am not writing on the book these days, but make slides for the lectures. That takes surprisingly long time. I have grown used to having slides to pick and choose from for any lecture, but I am starting from scratch here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>