<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mailund on the Internet</title>
    <link>https://mailund.dk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mailund on the Internet</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2020 - Thomas Mailund</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 07:01:59 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mailund.dk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi there,
This is my personal blog and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be confused with my word-webpages. I speak only for myself here, even when I write about work-related things.
I don&amp;rsquo;t write a lot here so it is more a web-page than a blog, but I do occasionally say something about what I am working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/books/</guid>
      <description>I enjoy writing and I&amp;rsquo;ve written bunch of books by now. Mostly about R programming, but also on a few other topics.
When I&amp;rsquo;m working on a book I haven&amp;rsquo;t sold yet, I usually put the draft on Leanpub where you can get it for free until it is done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/publications/</guid>
      <description>Textbooks 2020  String Algorithms in C: Efficient text representation and search Thomas MailundApress, Sep 30, ISBN-10: 148425919X, ISBN-13: 978-1484259191  2019   Introducing Markdown and Pandoc Thomas MailundApress, August 20, 2019,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/software/</guid>
      <description>I have written various software over the years. You can get a list of most of it at GitHub. Below is a list of software I have worked on recently (and I promise to still be maintaining).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — day 25</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 07:01:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-11/</guid>
      <description>On the last day of Christmas AoC gave to me an encryption problem, that is really a modular arithmetic problem.
If you decode the description—that is more cryptic than the mathematics—you find that we need to find secret keys by solving equations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 23 and 24</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 07:51:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-10/</guid>
      <description>Unexpectedly, I was allowed to play today—it is Christmas, after all—as long as I didn’t spend too much time at the computer. So I hurried up and solved today’s and yesterday’s puzzles quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — day 22</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 06:51:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-9/</guid>
      <description>This will be the last post I write before New Year. We have vacation in the house from tomorrow, and I won’t be hacking when I am supposed to be social—I am told.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 20 and 21</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 07:51:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-8/</guid>
      <description>Day 20: Jurassic Jigsaw Day 20 we get tiles for a puzzle, and we have to work out the puzzle from them. The tiles can be rotated or flipped, but we can connect them by identifying how edges match.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — day 19</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 06:51:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-7/</guid>
      <description>I will make this one quick, because I don’t have much time. Today, we are given some rules for what strings should look like, and we are to validate a set of strings and count how many are valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 17-18</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 08:51:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-6/</guid>
      <description>Well, today, my blogging catches up with my Advent of Code hacking. Just in time to fall behind again in the weekend. If that happens, I should be able to write up my weekend solutions on Monday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 14-16</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 18:51:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-5/</guid>
      <description>My posts are almost catching up to Advent of Code, which probably means that I will fall behind in the weekend. Quite likely, actually. I probably have time for solving the puzzles, but not writing about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 12-13</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 10:54:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-4/</guid>
      <description>I don’t have a lot of time today, so I will only describe the solutions for two days. I promise that I will catch up to the day the puzzles are released, but it probably won’t be until after the weekend…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 09–11</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 09:48:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-3/</guid>
      <description>Another day, another post with solutions to 2020 Advent of Code. I am slowly catching up with the actual puzzles, and I will probably get there soon. After that, there will probably be one day per post, except that I expect that the 24th and 25th will be something I leave for after Christmas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 06–08</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 06:48:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-2/</guid>
      <description>Ok, now that today’s puzzles are solved, I can go back and look at solutions to the previous days. Today, I will show you my solutions for days six through eight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of Code 2020 — days 01-05</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 04:48:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/aoc-2020-1/</guid>
      <description>While I wait for comments on the last chapters of my upcoming C-pointers book, I have some time on my hands. And since corona keeps me at home, I have to find something to keep me entertained.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OOP example in C</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/cpointer-oop-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 05:08:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/cpointer-oop-example/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing the chapter on function pointers in my C pointers book, and I want a nice example of how you can use them to implement rudimentary object-oriented programming with dynamic dispatch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference counting lists in C</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/c-refcount-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 06:59:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/c-refcount-list/</guid>
      <description>I was playing with reference counting garbage collection last week, for something I want to add to my C pointers book. That chapter is still far in the future, and moving further into the future as the book seems to grow in front of me, but one day I will get to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joys of Hashing</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/joys-of-hashing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 14:34:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/joys-of-hashing/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to post about it when The Joys of Hashing came out, but it is never too late to blow my own horn. It is out and you should get it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generators in C</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/c-generators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 14:02:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/c-generators/</guid>
      <description>Now that I am almost done with The Joys of Hashing, I am looking at the material I made last year for our Genome-scale Algorithms class. I implemented a toy read mapper as an example for the final project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elegant Scipy</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/elegant-scipy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 12:38:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/elegant-scipy/</guid>
      <description>I was a little disappointed about this. I had hoped it would give a good overview of Scipy, but instead, it is a bunch of examples that use it. It is not that the examples aren&amp;rsquo;t interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy queues</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/lazy-queues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 05:00:20 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/lazy-queues/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of the lazy lists I implemented in my previous post was to build lazy queues. Lazy lists give you constant time concatenation, which can be useful in itself, but I needed it to implement persistent functional queues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy lists</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/lazy-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 05:00:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/lazy-lists/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to write about lazy lists and lazy queues today, but I spent most of the day struggling with getting lazy evaluation to work. Finally, I convinced myself that something was broken in R, and I was justified in thinking that; upgrading to the most recent version resolved the issue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Promises, their environments, and how we evaluate them</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/promises-and-lazy-evaluation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 09:10:01 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/promises-and-lazy-evaluation/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how functions are evaluated? How you can have arguments that would raise errors, but do not, or how default arguments can be expressions that depend on function arguments that you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen yet when you define a function?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional lists and queues</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/functional-lists-and-queues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 05:00:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/functional-lists-and-queues/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to write something about function parameters, how these are passed as so-called &amp;ldquo;promises&amp;rdquo;, how these have associated scopes (and the consequences of that), and how they give us lazy evaluation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeing Further</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/seeing-further/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 15:57:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/seeing-further/</guid>
      <description>I also finished Seeing Further: The Story of Science, Discovery, and the Genius of the Royal Society yesterday. I found this a mixed back. When I bought it I thought it was a Bill Bryson book—I like those—but if I had checked the description just a little bit I would have seen that it is only edited by Bryson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Habit</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/the-power-of-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 15:45:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/the-power-of-habit/</guid>
      <description>In the weekend I finished The Power of Habit.
This is a very interesting book. Duhigg writes about how we are run by habit to a degree I had not imagined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises (CT Chapter 9)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 15:36:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter9/</guid>
      <description>Exercises Missing element You are given a sorted array, A. It contains n - 1 of the numbers from 1 to n. You should find the missing number.
You can use the property that for all numbers i less than the missing number you have A[i] == i, while for all i larger than the missing number you have A[i] == i - 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides (CT Chapter 9)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-slides-chapter9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 08:54:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-slides-chapter9/</guid>
      <description>Here are some slides for chapter 9 of Introduction to Computational Thinking.
 Slides Handouts Handouts with notes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erratas</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/erratas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 08:43:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/erratas/</guid>
      <description>To my utter shock, it turns out that I am not perfect. There are mistakes in my books!
A couple of readers made me aware of a typo in Functional Programming in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errata: Functional Programming in R</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/errata/fpinr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/errata/fpinr/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 2 The Structure of a Recursive Function, page 32: &amp;ldquo;Here I am assuming that is an integer…&amp;rdquo; should be &amp;ldquo;Here I am assuming that n is an integer…&amp;rdquo;
Chapter 3 Nested Functions and Scopes, page 53ff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environments and formulae</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/envs-and-formulae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 04:41:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/envs-and-formulae/</guid>
      <description>In my two previous posts on non-standard evaluation, Scoping rules and NSE and Overscoping and eval, I explained:
 How R finds the bindings of variables by looking through chains of environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises (CT Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 17:04:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter7/</guid>
      <description>I don’t really have a lot of exercises for the chapter on recursion. I had planned to combine recursion with divide-and-conquer, but now the two topics are split over two weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides (CT Chapter 7)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-slides-chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 15:33:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-slides-chapter7/</guid>
      <description>There is not a whole lot to say about recursion as such, but I&amp;rsquo;ve made a few slides. Half of it is just about how function calls work.
 Slides Handouts Handouts with notes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises (CT chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 10:54:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter5/</guid>
      <description>I’m on a roll today! Here are the exercises for chapter 5 of Introduction to Computational Thinking.
Let me know if you spot any errors; I am known to make some from time to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises (CT chapter 4)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 07:19:28 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter4/</guid>
      <description>I think I’m done with the exercises for chapter 4 of Introduction to Computational Thinking. Which is good, because I need to put them on Blackboard for my students this week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overscoping and eval</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/eval-and-overscoping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:23:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/eval-and-overscoping/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I used the lm function for an example of scope rules, but I left a few details out. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to muddy the example with too many details, so I chose to lie a little.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides for Computational Thinking (Chapter 5)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ct-slides-chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2018 12:12:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ct-slides-chapter5/</guid>
      <description>I just finished make slides for chapter 5 of Introduction to Computational Thinking that covers search and sorting algorithms.
The slides cover linear and binary search, insertion, selection and bubble sort, as well as bucket and radix sort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scoping Rules and NSE</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/scoping-rules-and-nse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 05:00:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/scoping-rules-and-nse/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, I wrote some tweets about how you have to be careful about scopes when you do &amp;ldquo;non-standard evaluation&amp;rdquo;. I cover this in both Metaprogramming in R and Domain-Specific Languages in R, but this tweet</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides (CT chapters 3 and 4)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-slides-chp3-and-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 17:04:47 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-slides-chp3-and-4/</guid>
      <description>I played around a little with my slides for chapter three of Introduction to Computational Thinking and made slides for chapter four.
It takes surprisingly long to make these; I had expected to be done with the five chapters I use in my class this year a few weeks ago but I still have three chapters to go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercises (CT chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 16:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-exercises-chapter3/</guid>
      <description>I have cleaned up the exercises for chapter three of Introduction to Computational Thinking. I’m still not exactly sure how best to provide them to my students, or if I can figure out some way to automatically test answers so they can be more interactive, but I have listed them below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complexity Exercises</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-complexity-exercises/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 10:20:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/ctib-complexity-exercises/</guid>
      <description>In the second lesson that I teach in our Computational Thinking in Bioinformatics I cover algorithmic complexity. It is chapter four in my (draft) book on the topic: Introduction to Computational Thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides for Computational Thinking (Chapter 3)</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/compbio-chapter-3-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 13:40:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/compbio-chapter-3-slides/</guid>
      <description>I’m teaching four weeks of a class called Computational Thinking in Bioinformatics this year (the other weeks are taught by colleagues).
It is this class that got me started on my book on the topic: Introduction to Computational Thinking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coming Storm</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/the-coming-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 08:06:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/the-coming-storm/</guid>
      <description>If you are a member of Audible—and if you like audiobooks I think you should be—then they now give you two of six selected books for free every month. They call this Audible Originals, and while you only get six books to choose from, I am not complaining about getting something for free.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Premarkdown Plugins</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/premd-plugins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 14:25:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/premd-plugins/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a preprocessor for Markdown documents. I write all my books in Markdown, so this is something I have wanted to do for a while, to scratch a few itches I have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluent Python</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/fluent-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 09:11:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/fluent-python/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading Fluent Python. This is a really nice book on Python programming. It is not an introduction to Python programming, and it is not about specific packages, such as SciPy or Scikit-learn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Books Page</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/new-books-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 06:32:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/new-books-page/</guid>
      <description>I have set up a page for the books I have written. Nothing fancy there, it is just a list together with the cover text, but it does collect all my books on one single page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Blog</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/posts/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 08:02:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/posts/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so, I have had a lot of problems with keeping Wordpress and various plugins up to date on my old mailund.dk blog. Considering that I don&amp;rsquo;t write a whole lot of posts there, I decided that it simply wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth the effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errata: Functional Data-Structures in R</title>
      <link>https://mailund.dk/errata/fdsinr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mailund.dk/errata/fdsinr/</guid>
      <description>One big regret I have about this book is that I didn’t implement the pattern matching code from Domain-Specific Languages in R before this book. Pattern matching makes implementing data structures much easier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
